<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Blood Care</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Donors Locations</string>
    <string name="appname">Blood Care</string>
    <string name="design">Developed By</string>
    <string name="Signin">Login</string>
    <string name="Signup">Signup</string>


    <!-- Strings related to login -->
    <string name="Email">Email</string>
    <string name="Password">Password</string>
    <string name="fullName">Full Name</string>
    <string name="aadhar">Aadhar Number</string>
    <string name="fact">

<u>Facts about blood needs</u>\n\n
1. Every year our nation requires about 5 Crore units of blood out of\n
which only a meager 2.5 Crore units of blood are available.

2. The gift of blood in the gift of life. There is no substitute for
human blood.\n

3. Every two seconds someone needs blood.\n

4.More than 3,000 blood donations are needed every day.\n
5.A total of 30 million blood components are transfused each year.\n
6.The average red blood cell transfusion is approximately 3 pints.\n
7.The blood type most often requested by hospitals is Type O.\n
8. More than 1 million new people are diagnosed with cancer each
year Many of them will need blood, sometimes daily during the
chemotherapy treatment.\n
9.A single car accident victim can require as many a 100 unito!
blood.\n\n

<u>Facts about the blood supply</u>\n\n

1.Blood cannot be manufactured -it can only come from generous
donors.\n
2.Type O negative blood Red cells) can be transfused to patients
of all blood types. It is always in greal demand and often in short
supply.\n
3.Type AB positive plasma can be transfused to patients of all other
blood type AB plasma is also usually in short supply.\n\n

<u>Facts about the blood donation process</u>\n\n

1. Donating blood is safe process Sterile needle is used only
once for each donor and then discarded.\n
2.Blood donation is a simple four-step process registration
medical history and mine physical donation and refreshments.\n
3.The average adult has about 10 units of blood in his body
Roughly 1 unit is given during a donation.\n
4.A healthy donor may donate red blood cells every 56 days, on
double red cells every 112 days.\n
5.A healthy donor may donate platelets as few days apart but
maximum of 24 times year.\n
6.All donated blood is tested for HIV, hepatitis B and C syphilis and
other infectious diseases before it can be transfused to patients.\n\n

<u>Facts about blood and its components.</u>\n\n

1. Blood makes up about 7 percent of your body weight\n
2.There are four types of transfusable products that can be deemed
from blood Red cells, platelets, plasma and cryoprecipitate
Typically, two or three of these are produced from a unit of donate
whole blood-hence each donation can help save up to three lives.\n
3.Donors can give either whole blood or specific blood components
only. The process of donating specific blood components - red
cells, plasma or platelets - is called apheresis.\n
4.One transfusion dose of platelets can be obtained through one
apheresis donation of platelets or by combining the platelets
derived from five whole blood donations.\n
5.Donated platelets must be used within five days of collection.\n
6.Healthy bone marrow makes a constant supply of red cells.\n
plasma and platelets. The body will replenish the elements given
during a blood donation- some in a matter of hours and others in
matter of weeks.\n\n

<u>Facts about donors</u>\n\n
1.The number one reason donors say they give blood is because
they want to help others.\n
2.Two most common reasons cited by people who dont give blood
are Never thought about it and I dont like needles.\n
3.One donation can help save the lives of up to three people.\n
4. If you began donating blood at age 18 and donated every 90 days
until you reached 60, you would have donated 30 gallons of blood,
potentially helping save more than 500 lives.\n
5.Only 7 percent of people in India have O-negative blood type
O negative blood type donors are universal donors as their blood
can be given to people of all blood types.\n
6.Type O negative blood is needed in emergencies before the
patients blood type is known and with whom who need blood.\n
7.Thirty five percent of people have Type O positive ar negative
blood.\n
8.04 percent of people have AB blood type A type blood
donors are universal donor of plasma, which is often used in emergencies for newborn and patients requiring massive transfusion.

</string>


</resources>
